SONU SHARMA

Bengaluru, Karnataka 560103 ◆ 981 085 9445 ◆ sonu200790@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Qualified Senior Web Application Developer with 6.5 years of experience in Software Development and deep interest in web technologies and want to utilize my skills in creating an extraordinary experience for the company's technical audience

SKILLS

Angular 2, 4, 6, 7, 8

Javascript, jQuery

Node JS(learning)

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

MVC FrameWork

MySQL Database

Rest API

WORK HISTORY

Senior Web Application Developer, 03/2018 to Current

Builder.ai – Gurgaon, HARYANA

Builder Tracker:

Description: It is a task tracking system for developers(like JIRA, PIVOTAL TRACKER), so product managers can create story for developers and developers manage the status of task based on the current phase.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Working as a senior Web developer, and working from base of this project. so set up whole architecture
 of project.
- Added continuous integration and code coverage for unit test cases.
- Set up whole fronted web application using Angular4 and now its current version is 8.
- Developed Project Module.
- Developed Admin Module.
- Added Lazy loading for modules.
- Added AOT(Ahead of time compilation). for performance enhancement.
- Added Web sockets, so every one can get real update.
- Integrated Dragula library for Drag and Drop for columns.
- Integrated third party library like CKEditor5.
- Optimisation for performance boostup
- Added PWA(Progressive Web Application).
- Managing junior developers in this project.

Environment: Angular 2/4/6/7/8, Javascript, Bootstrap 4, Typescript, Html, CSS

Web Developer, 05/2017 to 03/2018

Softomozo – Gurgaon, HARYANA

Description: It is a complete solutions for Education industry like fee application, attendance application for universities, schools and colleges.

Roles & Responsibilities.

- Developed Workflow components which will be used in whole application and unit testing them using angular4, Bootstarap4.
- Developed Admin Module from where Admin can view details of all the hostels, assign hostel, configure leave for students, assign attendants and wardens for hostels.
- Created Some functionality of Tableu which are using in all applications.
- Developed Warden Module where warden can view details of hostels assigned to him/her.
- Created API for workflow using Lumen framework.

Environment: Angular2, Bootstrap4, Typescript, PHP, Laravel, Mysql.

Software Developer, 07/2015 to 05/2017

Chetu Inc. – Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Benetech-HR:

Description: It is a system which manage employee benefit and payroll. It is a US based project. There is a IRS department which handle employee data so IRS department have webservices(API) for same and we will use in our system.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Developed the admin module for group admin where admin and group admin can show list of employees of a company.
- Building the centralized library for all the components shared among different applications and unit testing them.
- Created REST APIs in PHP.

Environment: Angular2, PHP, Javascript, Html, CSS

Software Developer, 01/2014 to 07/2015

Finoit Software Pvt Ltd – Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Ourannual:

Description: Thinking through the Login scheme, I would like to see people associate with a school when they login, so they could potentially be notified of activity in that school in the future. It would probably also make sense to have them select their graduation year, even if their year is out of the range of saved books - IE they might be logging into look at their parents or grandparents.

Roles & Responsibilities:

• Implemented User Module

• Support designer to fix design issues.

Environment: Javascript, Angular2/Typescript.

Chummy(Frontend and Web services):

Description: An Android LockScreen Application.

- Write Web services.
- Create Admin Panel.
- Implement the Push notification in Android.
- To perform enhancements and Bug fixes.

Environment: Javascript, PHP/MYSQL, Zend Framework

EDUCATION

B.Tech (67%): Electrical, Electronics And Communications Engineering, 06/2012

Raj Kumar Goel Institue Of Technology - Ghaziabad

12th (71%): Science, 07/2006 Avanti Vai Inter School - Agra

10th(65%): Science, 07/2004 Avanti Vai Inter School - Agra